<resources>
    <string name="app_name">CookAdvisor</string>
    <string name="action_settings" translatable="false">Settings</string>
    <string name="action_share" translatable="false">Share</string>
    <string name="add">NEW</string>
    <string name="title_activity_detail" translatable="false">DetailActivity</string>
    <string name="start">START</string>
    <string name="reset_time">RESET</string>
    <string name="advice_label">Advice</string>
    <string name="no_advices">No advices</string>
    <string name="title_activity_edit" translatable="false">EditActivity</string>
    <string name="hours">HOUR</string>
    <string name="min">MIN</string>
    <string name="sec">SEC</string>
    <string name="title">Title:</string>
    <string name="save">SAVE</string>
    <string name="defvalue" translatable="false">00</string>
    <string name="hint_title">Please, insert title</string>
    <string name="hint_advice">Please, insert your advice</string>
    <string name="hint_data">Please, fill all fields!</string>
    <string name="hint_time">Please, insert valid time!</string>
    <string name="edit">EDIT</string>
    <string name="delete">DELETE</string>
    <string name="Delete">Delete</string>
    <string name="Cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="done">Done!</string>
    <string name="is_preparing">is preparing</string>
    <string name="banner_ad_unit_id" translatable="false">ca-app-pub-3940256099942544/6300978111</string>

    <string name="pasta">Pasta</string>
    <string name="egg">egg</string>
    <string name="egg_soft">Egg soft-boiled</string>
    <string name="egg_medium">Egg medium-boiled</string>
    <string name="egg_hard">Egg hard-boiled</string>
    <string name="sausage">Sausage</string>
    <string name="rice">rice</string>
    <string name="white_rice">Rice white</string>
    <string name="brown_rice">Rice brown</string>
    <string name="corn">Corn</string>
    <string name="potato">Potato</string>
    <string name="carrot">Carrot</string>
    <string name="chicken">chicken</string>
    <string name="chicken_breasts">Chicken breasts</string>
    <string name="fish">Fish</string>
    <string name="porridge">Oatmeal (porridge)</string>
    <string name="rolled_oats">Oat Flakes (Rolled Oats)</string>
    <string name="oat">oat</string>
    <string name="peas">peas</string>
    <string name="peas_fresh">Peas fresh</string>
    <string name="peas_dried">Peas dried</string>
    <string name="beans">beans</string>
    <string name="dried_beans">Beans dried</string>
    <string name="beet">Beat</string>
    <string name="buckwheat">Buckwheat</string>

    <string name="advice_egg_soft">Soft-boiled egg - the white is solid, but the yolk is still runny. Gently lower the eggs into boiling water to cover them by about 1 inch. Add a little salt to the water - it helps to clean eggs from the shell. Set a timer! After timer ends, use a slotted spoon to transfer eggs to the cold bath and let them cool. Use the side of a small spoon to crack and remove the pointed end of the egg, making a hole in the shell large enough to fit the spoon. Or use egg scissors, if you have them. Serve in an egg cup for breakfast. Enjoy! :)</string>
    <string name="advice_egg_medium">Medium-boiled egg - the yolk is solid but still dark orange-yellow, moist, and dense in the middle. Beautiful and delicious quartered on a salad. Gently lower the eggs into boiling water to cover them by about 1 inch. Add a little salt to the water - it helps to clean eggs from the shell. Set a timer! After timer ends, use a slotted spoon to transfer eggs to the cold bath and let them cool. Softly tap the egg against the counter to crack the shell, carefully peel. If the shells are stubborn, try peeling them under running water. The fresher the egg, the more attached the shell, so for boiling, older eggs are preferable. Enjoy! :)</string>
    <string name="advice_egg_hard">Hard-boiled egg - the yolk is completely solid, light yellow, and crumbly, with no sign of the telltale green or gray ring around the yolk that is caused by overcooking. Perfect for egg salad or deviled eggs. Gently lower the eggs into boiling water to cover them by about 1 inch. Add a little salt to the water - it helps to clean eggs from the shell. Set a timer! After timer ends, use a slotted spoon to transfer eggs to the cold bath and let them cool. Softly tap the egg against the counter to crack the shell, carefully peel. If the shells are stubborn, try peeling them under running water. The fresher the egg, the more attached the shell, so for boiling, older eggs are preferable. Enjoy! :)</string>
    <string name="advice_pasta">Bring a large pot of well-salted water to a boil. Salt the water generously - only 10 percent of the salt in the cooking water will be absorbed. Boil the pasta according to package directions until al dente (generally it is about 10 minutes). Add a spoon of oil to the cooking water and keep stirring periodically to ensure even cooking and to keep pasta from clumping together or sticking to the bottom of the pot. To test a piece of pasta, remove it from the boiling water and bite into it to determine if it is done. Once cooked, drain it well and don\'t rinse. Shake the colander to remove any excess water. Rinsing will cool down the pasta, but it removes both the surface starch that keeps it firm and its essential nutrients. Only pasta for salad should be rinsed. Return the drained pasta to the still-warm cooking pot, and combine it with the sauce there to keep hot until ready to be served. Enjoy! :)</string>
    <string name="advice_sausage">Fill a large saucepan with enough water to cover sausages easily. For 4 sausages, 4 cups (about 1 liter) of water should be more than enough. Be sure to use a pan large enough so that the water falls at least a few inches below the rim. Place the sausages into boiling water. To prevent hot splashes, lower the sausages in one-by-one with a set of tongs or another long utensil. Don\'t drop them in. When all the sausages are in the water, turn the heat down so that the boiling reduces to a gentle simmer. Set a timer! After the sausages are finished boiling, remove them from hot water and put into the cold water for a second, then dry them off carefully with a paper towel. Serve the sausages with any combination of mustard, ketchup, relish, onion, tomato, cheese, or sauerkraut. Enjoy! :)</string>
    <string name="advice_rice">Wash and rinse the rice really well, until the water is clear. Drain. Place in a saucepan with double the amount of water and a little salt and stir once. For most rice, use a 1:2 ratio of one cup of rice to two cups of water . Measure a half cup of uncooked rice per person and scale this ratio up or down depending on how much you\'re making. Set a timer! Don\'t stir the rice throughout the cooking - it will make it stodgy. Don\'t cook the rice on too high a heat - it may stick and burn on the bottom before the rest of the rice is cooked. Cover the pot and turn the heat down to low. Don\'t take off the lid while the rice is cooking — this lets the steam out and affects the cooking time. When done, the rice will be firm but tender, and no longer crunchy. It is fine if it\'s slightly sticky but shouldn\'t be gummy. If there is still water left in the pan when the rice is done, tilt the pan to drain it off. Turn off the heat and let stand a few minutes, covered. This steams the rice just a little more. Remove the lid and fluff: Fluff the rice with a spoon or a fork, and let it sit for a few moments to "dry out" and lose that wet, just-steamed texture. Serve the rice: Leftover rice keeps well in the fridge for several days, so you can make extra ahead to serve later. Enjoy! :)</string>
    <string name="advice_corn">Shuck your corn husks, then rinse off the corn. Boil the Water. Drop the Corn in the Water: Carefully drop in freshly shucked corn into the boiling water. Poke the ears a little bit so each side gets covered in water. Cook the Corn: Cover the pot with a lid and lower heat to medium. Set a timer. Serve the Corn: Serve corn immediately with butter and salt. Enjoy! :)</string>
    <string name="advice_potato">You can boil potatoes either whole or cubed — both ways work fine. Make sure the whole  potatoes or cubed potatoes are roughly the same size. This way, they will all cook at the same rate. You can boil potatoes with their skins on or off. It\'s  very easy to peel off the skins after the potatoes are cooked. Cover the potatoes with an inch or two of cold water. Stir the salt into the water so that it dissolves. Set the pan over medium–high heat and bring the water to a boil. Once boiling, reduce the heat to a bare simmer to cook the potatoes. Set a timer! Cubed potatoes will cook more quickly than whole potatoes; smaller potatoes will cook more quickly than larger potatoes. Begin checking the potatoes after around 5 minutes of boiling; most potatoes will be done in 15–20 minutes. The potatoes are done when they are tender all the way through. You can test this by poking the potato with a fork. Drain the potatoes. Enjoy!</string>
    <string name="advice_carrot">A lot of the carrot\'s flavor and nutrients is near its surface. So often it\'s better just not to peel the carrot, and just wash it thoroughly. Place carrots in a pot of cold water: vegetables must be only little covered with water, to minimize nutrient loss. Set a timer. Bring the water to the boil. Cook, covered, until the carrots are as done as you like them. Try testing them with a fork. The fork should slide in easily enough. Drain the carrots. You can serve them as is, or with a bit of butter, salt, or other herbs and spices. Enjoy!</string>
    <string name="advice_chicken">If you are boiling a frozen chicken, make sure to the meat thaw prior to cooking. The liquid used to cook the chicken can be as simple as water, or chicken broth, apple cider, dry white wine, or a combination. Other ways to flavor the cooking liquid and the chicken include adding onion wedges, carrot pieces, celery pieces, garlic cloves, bouillon granules, herbs, salt, and lemon juice or peel. Take a pot with two-thirds of water or just enough liquid to cover the amount of meat you are going to cook. The amount of waiting time you will need depends on the chicken parts you are cooking. If you are cooking a whole, you may need an hour. For chicken breasts, 30 minutes may be good enough. If you are boiling smaller chicken parts such as wings or thighs, you will need to check at least every 15 minutes. When done, chicken should be white and be easily pulled apart with hands or a fork. Add boiled chicken to salads, stir-fries, or fajitas. Season as desired with salt, pepper, Italian herbs, or cooking sauces. Enjoy!</string>
    <string name="advice_fish">Boiling fish is a technique that will work well with any style of fish. Wash the fish in cold water, and make sure it is clean. Fill a pot with enough cold water to cover the entire fish. Pour in 1 tsp. (5 ml) of table salt, and 1 to 1.5 tsp. (5 to 7.5 ml) of lemon juice. If you don\'t have lemon juice, you may substitute with vinegar. Place the fish into the pot, and set it on top of the stove. Turn the heat on medium so that the water comes to a slow boil. It is very important that the water boils slowly, so that the fish has enough time to cook thoroughly.  For a much richer flavor, can add stock to the boiling water. Chop up a white onion and several carrots into bite-size pieces, and add them to the water along with 2 or 3 cloves, salt, pepper, and vinegar. Boil your fish until it is cooked through. As a general rule, for thicker, large fish such as catfish or tuna, allow it to cook for approximately 8 minutes for every 1 pound (.45 kg) of fish, and thinner fish such as tilapia or sole should cook for approximately 5 minutes for every 1 pound (.45 kg) of fish. Remove the fish from the water once it is cooked, and serve.</string>
    <string name="advice_porridge">The basic ratio for making steel-cut oatmeal is 1 cup of oats to 3 to 4 cups of water. Boil water, add oats, reduce heat, and simmer. Start tasting the oatmeal around the 20 minute mark and keep cooking until you\'re happy with it. The longer you cook the oats, the softer they will become. When stirring the oats, be sure to scrap the bottom of the pot; this will prevent the oats from sticking to the pot. If you wish to flavor your oatmeal, you may add some salt or butter. Other flavorings, such as milk, honey, berries, and nuts are best left for the end. This is due to the long cooking time. The oats are ready to eat immediately. You can also let the oats cool and then store them in an airtight container in the fridge for up to a week. The oats will thicken in the fridge; stir a little milk or water into them when reheating to loosen.</string>
    <string name="advice_rolled_oats">Pour 2 cups of water for every 1 cup of uncooked rolled oats you are cooking into a saucepan large enough to hold twice the amount of oats and water. Bring the water to a boil. Both rolled oats and old fashioned oatmeal are the same thing; they just have two different names. This type of oatmeal is your standard oatmeal, and it looks like flakes. Put the oats into the water.  Bring the oatmeal to a simmer and stir often. Eventually, the oatmeal will begin to absorb the water and thicken. For a savory oatmeal, add a pinch of salt and some butter. For a sweeter oatmeal, stir in some honey or maple syrup. You can also use some brown sugar and cinnamon. For a hearty oatmeal, stir in some raisins or dried cranberries. You can also use sliced almonds or crumbled walnuts or pecans.  Cook the oatmeal for about five minutes, or until you get the texture and consistency you want. The longer you cook your oatmeal, the thicker and softer it will become. Once the oatmeal has cooked, consider covering the pot with a lid and let it sit (off the heat) for 2 minutes. This will allow the oatmeal to absorb any extra moisture.</string>
    <string name="advice_peas_fresh">If the peas are fresh you need to remove them from the pea pod. Judge how much water it would take to cover the peas, then add that amount of water to a pot. Set the pot on high, and let it boil. When it comes to a boil, quickly add the peas and turn the heat down to medium high. Let the peas cook for 3 minutes if fresh, 4 minutes if frozen. Enjoy!</string>
	<string name="advice_peas_dried">Dried peas and other pulses should be well rinsed and drained just before use. When boiled, good quality dried peas naturally collapse into a puree. This indicates that the soup is ready; cooking times in recipes are only approximate guidelines. Salt added to the water, either on its own or in meats, may prevent peas from forming in puree. An immersion blender is a handy way to help the process along. Once boiling point is achieved, boil gently over a low heat with a tightly covered lid to minimize evaporation. If the heat is too high, soup at the bottom of the pot will stick and scorch. Whole yellow peas should be boiled gently on their own until puree is achieved, since the addition of salt or salted meat interferes with the puree process. To achieve optimal flavour, vegetables, meat and meat stock should be added no sooner than one hour before serving.</string>
	<string name="advice_beans">The night before you plan to cook (or 10 to 14 hours ahead), soak the beans to reduce cooking time and help them cook more evenly. Drain the beans from their soaking water and rinse them gently under water. Transfer the beans to a heavy cooking pot. Add the aromatics, if using. Cover the beans with an inch of water. Bring them to a boil over medium-high heat. Once boiling, reduce the heat to low and bring the beans to a very gentle simmer. Cook the beans for one hour, and then begin checking for doneness. Depending on their age, size, and variety, beans can take anywhere from an hour to three hours to cook through. Be patient. When beans are tender but still too firm to enjoy eating, add the salt. Continue simmering until the beans are as tender and creamy as you like them. Add more salt to taste.</string>
    <string name="advice_beet">Fill a saucepan with water and a little salt. Add a half a teaspoon of salt. This will help flavor the beetroot as it cooks. Bring the water to a boil over high heat. Wash and scrub any dirt off the beetroot. Cut off the stem and tail ends and discard the scraps. You can leave your beetroot whole when boiling or you can cut it into cubes, which will reduce cooking time. Don\'t bother peeling your beetroot if you leave them whole. Make sure the water covers the beetroot by a few inches. Once the water is boiling, carefully add the whole or cubed beetroot. If using whole beetroot, boil them for 45 minutes to 1 hour. If using cubed beetroot, boil the cubes for 15 to 20 minutes. Poke the beetroot with a fork or knife. It should be tender enough that the utensil easily slides in and out. If it is hard to poke or gets stuck, the beetroot needs to boil longer. Once the beetroot is tender, drain the hot water and run cold water over it. Then, rub off the skin using a paper towel.  Use your boiled beetroot as called for in another recipe, or mash and serve with butter. Season the beetroot with salt and pepper.</string>
    <string name="advice_buckwheat">Check for any debris which may have entered in packing, rinse with water. The ratio of water to buckwheat is 1 cup buckwheat, to 2 cups of water. Fill a pot with enough cold water and teaspoon of salt and set to high heat. Once the water has started boiling, add the buckwheat. Then reduce the heat and simmer, covered, until the liquid has been absorbed. This should take about 20 minutes. Turn off the heat and let stand, covered, until all of the water has been absorbed (about 5 minutes). Fluff with a fork and serve with butter.</string>

</resources>
